Good afternoon everybody
大家下午好
Welcome good to see you
欢迎很高兴见到你
And welcome to all those who are watching on videotape as well
也欢迎正在看录像的同学们
I want to clear up. I realized after the last lecture
我想重新整理一下上节课的内容
That I didn't explain the idea of peak memory utilization very well to you
我意识到我没有很好地解释峰值内存利用率这个概念
So I want to just explain that it's an important idea and I want to make sure that we have it clear
我想要说明这是一个很重要的概念，我希望大家都能够理解
So if you recall from we're executing a series a sequence of requests
你回忆起我们正在执行一系列请求
R0,R1,R2...R(k)...R(n-1)
R0，R1，R2，...，R(k)，...，R(N-1)
And at any point in time after k+1 requests
并且在 k+1 请求之后的任何时间点
We have H(k)
我们有 H(k)
Which is the heap size
这是堆大小
After k1 requests
在 k+1 次请求之后
Now we have a P(k) which is the aggregate
我们现在有一个 P(k) 的聚合
The sum of all of the payloads
所有有效载荷的总和
After k+1 requests
在 k+1 请求之后
Okay so what we're trying to do with this pk measure
我们正在尝试用这个 p(k)
This aggregate payload is at any point in time so
此聚合有效负载在任何时间点都是如此
As we execute requests one after the other
当我们一个接一个地执行请求时
The sum of all the payloads in the heap is going to either increase or decrease right so if we execute an allocate
如果我们执行分配，堆中所有有效负载的总和将增加或减少
Then the size of the payloads will increase
然后有效载荷的大小将增加
If we execute a free the size of all those allocated payloads will decrease right so
如果我们执行 free，则所有分配的有效负载的大小将会减小
So as we're executing this the sequence of requests these
因此，当我们执行这些请求序列时
The aggregate the sum of all the payloads is going to be increasing and decreasing
所有有效载荷的总和将会增加和减少
Okay and so what we're capturing with the sum of all these payloads is like a perfect allocator that has no overheads
我们用所有这些有效载荷的总和捕获的东西就像一个没有开销的完美分配器
And even more so one that we can
甚至
Where we're allowed to compact blocks
我们被允许压缩块
So the sum of all of the payloads is the minimum possible heap size
因此，所有有效负载的总和是最小可能的堆大小
It's the minimum possible number of bytes required by those allocated blocks
这是分配的块所需的最小字节数
Okay so it's very very aggressive and it's impossible to achieve
所以它非常完美的，但是无法实现
But we're going to use that as sort of a best case
但我们将把它作为一种最好的案例
Okay
好的
And so to measure a P(k) memory utilization
因此，要测量 P(k) 内存利用率
After K+1 requests
在 K+1 请求之后
Which will denote U(k)
哪个将表示 U(k)
That's going to be equal to
这将等于
The max
最大
For all i <=k
对于所有 i <= k
Of our aggregate payloads
我们的总有效载荷
Divided by the size of the heap after after k+1 requests
除以在 k+1 个请求之后的堆的大小
Okay so what we're doing with this max is
那么我们正在做的最大化的是
We're remembering the high-water mark
我们记得高水位线
You know as our aggregate payloads
当聚集有效负载增加或者减少时
Increase and decrease we're remembering the high-water mark
我们记住高水位线
Right so that was sort of the worst that was like the biggest set of payloads that we had
这是最糟糕的，就像我们拥有的最大有效载荷一样
And then so the max is remembering that high-water mark
最大值就是这个高水位线
And then we're dividing by the total size of the heap in order to get an efficiency measure
然后我们将其除以堆的总大小以获得效率度量
Okay so this max
所以这个最大值
P(k) is the best we could have done divided by the total the total heap size
我们最好用 P(K) 来除以总堆大小的总和
Okay so yes
好的，是的
[student speaking]
学生提问
Well that the allocator keeps track of of how big the heap
那么分配器会跟踪堆的大小
So that's pretty easy right
所以这很简单吧
So as every time it does,every time it calls sbreak
因此，每当它发生时，每次它调用 「sbreak」
It just that adds to the size of the heap and remember we're...
只是增加了堆的大小
We're assuming that the heap in this case is always increasing okay so
我们假设在这种情况下堆总是增加
But even if we allow the heap size to decrease
但即使我们允许堆大小减少
Could just if the allocator is controlling the size of the heap by calls to sbreak
只是分配器可以通过调用 「sbreak」 来控制堆的大小
Okay so is that clear
好的就是这么清楚
So for U(k) the higher the better
因此对于 U(k) 越高越好
Okay and for any sequence of allocates and free
好的，任何分配和释放序列
This max P(k) will be the same
这个最大 P(k) 将是相同的
Okay that's constant right
这是常数
But what varies is H(k) and that depends on how efficient your allocator is using the heap storage
但是 H(k) 是变化，它取决于分配器使用堆存储的效率
Okay yes question
好的，是的问题
[student speaking]
学生提问
So what we're doing is at any point in time
所以我们正在做的是在任何时间
After we're after k+1 requests
在我们完成 k+1 次请求之后
We're evaluating the utilization of a heap up till that point so it should be k
我们正在评估堆的利用率，直到那时它应该是 k
[student speaking]
学生提问
For i <=k
for i <= k
Oh I'm sorry
哦，对不起
Yeah sorry good good catch so that should be an i right
对不起，所以这应该是 i
We want to look at all the requests that came before
我们想查看之前的所有请求
Okay any other questions
还有其他任何问题
Okay all right so last time we looked at some simple the basics of dynamic storage allocation
好的，所以上次我们看一下简单的动态存储分配的基础知识
Today we're going to look at some more sophisticated techniques using
今天我们将看一些更复杂的技术
Different data structures to store the free list primarily
主要用于存储空闲列表的不同数据结构
We'll look at implicit allocators
我们将看一下隐式分配器
So we'll get a sort of a brief survey of how garbage collectors work
我们将对垃圾收集器的工作方式进行简要学习
And we'll just look at one,just one very simple kind of garbage collector
我们只看一个，只是一个非常简单的垃圾收集器
But it will give you an idea of what that means
但它会让你知道这意味着什么
And then we'll finish up
然后我们将完成
We'll finish up by looking at all the ways you can get yourself into trouble
我们将通过在使用动态分配储存空间中可能遇到的问题
By using dynamically allocated storage
来进行这堂课的学习
So once you start dynamically allocating storage
一旦你开始动态分配存储
Things can go really bad really quickly
事情真的很快就会很糟糕
And so we'll go over some of those bad things that can happen and
所以我们将讨论一些可能发生的坏事
Try to alert you to those so you don't do them in your programs
尽量提醒你，以免在程序中执行此操作
Okay so we looked at how to store a free list in this sort of implicit form by just walking the entire heap
好的，我们看看如何通过走完整个堆来存储这种隐式形式的空闲列表
And and there by sort of being able to visit all the free blocks
并且能够访问所有空闲区块
But we can do better
但我们可以做得更好
If we store the free list using a doubly linked list
如果我们用双向链表来储存空闲列表
So in we call these explicit free lists
我们称之为「显式空闲列表」
So the idea with an explicit free list is that
因此，显式空闲列表的想法是
We put pointers
我们把指针
We put the pointers that implement the doubly linked list
我们用指针实现了双链表
Inside the the body of the of a free block
把指针指向一个空闲块的里面
Say where the old payload used to go so
说旧的有效载荷曾经去过的地方
Allocated blocks look exactly the same as they did before right
分配的块看起来与它们之前完全相同
There's a header, optional boundary tag footer
有一个头部标记，可选的边界标记脚部
And then this the payload and any padding
然后是有效载荷和任何填充
Free blocks though the allocator is not allowed to touch anything in the inside the payload of an allocated block
通过分配器的空闲块不允许触摸分配块的有效负载内部的任何内容
But free blocks are free right nobody's using them
但空闲区块是空闲的，没有人使用它们
And so the allocator can put the
所以分配器可以让
The pointers that implement the data structure inside the what was the old payload
实现数据结构的指针指向曾今是负载的地方
So logically this is just a simple doubly linked list,okay that you've all seen before
所以逻辑上这只是一个简单的双向链表，你以前都见过
But actually these things can be anywhere in memory right
但实际上这些东西可以在内存中的任何地方
And so you know here we have...
所以在这里
We have a block of size 6
我们有一个大小为 6 的块
And it has a 4 word pointer that points to some other link
它有一个 4 字指针指向其他链接
And it has a backwards pointer that points to
它有一个反向指针指向
This block which happens to be have a greater memory address than it
这个恰好具有比它更大的内存地址的块
Okay so just the idea is you can't...
好的，只是这个想法是你不能......
You know unless you go to great pains to maintain
你知道除非你付出巨大的努力来维持
This sort of address ordered structure
这种地址有序结构
These blocks can be sort of scattered anywhere in memory
这些块可以分散在内存中的任何位置
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh yeah so this is after several
哦，是的，所以这是几次之后
You know just sort of indefinite number of malloc and frees and
你知道一些无限数量的 malloc 和 free
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh yeah good question
哦，是的好问题
So the question is what would happen if you free to a block that was in between two free blocks
所以问题是如果你释放一个位于两个空闲块之间的块会发生什么
And so you have to coalesce it gets a little tricky and I'll show you in a second
你必须合并它有点棘手，我会在一秒钟给你看
Good now allocating oh yes questions
什么问题？
[student speaking]
学生提问
So the question is what happens with locality
所以问题是局部会发生什么
So you still get block locality
所以你仍然得到块局部性
You know use blocks are still contiguous
你知道使用块仍然是连续的
But if you're scanning sort of a set of allocated blocks it would be better
但如果你正在扫描一组已分配的块，那就更好了
If you could keep them all contiguous right
如果你能保持它们所有的连续
And so there's a you know that's a trade-off I don't
这里有一些权衡
It gets difficult if you think how can you maintain
如果你考虑你能维持下去会很困难
So you don't really care about the locality of free blocks right, you're just walking a linked list
所以你真的不关心空闲块的位置，你只是遍历一个链表
Well no I shouldn't say that that's
好吧，不，我不应该这样说
If you're walking that list,if you hit one free block
如果你正在走这个列表，如果你命中来一个空闲块
It would bring in a whole page so it'd be better
它会带来一整页，所以它会更好
If you were walking, if the list you know if as much of that list was contained within that page
如果你正在遍历列表中，你知道该页中是否包含尽可能多的列表
So even that's, so you would benefit
所以即便如此，你也会受益
You could benefit eat with both allocated blocks because applications would be using them and with free blocks
你可以使用两个分配的块受益，因为应用程序将使用它们和空闲块
Because the allocator would be walking that free list
因为分配器会走那个空闲列表
Question
问题？
[student speaking]
学生提问
That's a really good question
这是一个非常好的问题
So the question is could would it be possible for an application to give hints to the allocator
问题是应用程序是否有可能给分配器提供一些提示
That would improve the allocators performance or memory utilization
这会增加分配器性能或内存利用率
The the answer you absolutely could
答案你绝对可以
But it's if you did it wouldn't be a general-purpose allocator
但是，如果你这样做，它将不是一个通用的分配器
So like malloc is a general-purpose allocator
因此 malloc 是一个通用的分配器
So and it provides no there's no option
所以它并没有提供任何选择
It doesn't provide any arguments in its interface for passing that information in
它在其接口中不提供任何用于传递该信息的参数
But it absolutely if it had some knowledge about the future behavior of a program that could benefit
但它如果对某个程序的未来行为有一定的了解，它可以从中受益
Right so especially I consider you always have this decision when you place an allocated block
对，所以特别是我认为当你放置一个已分配的块时，你总是需要决定
Whether to split that block or not
是否拆分该块
Well if you knew that you were going to get a request
如果你知道你会得到一个请求
You know if you split that block and you knew that you were going to get requests
你知道如果你拆分那块，你知道你会在之后首先得到原始块的大小的请求
Coming in the future first for sizes of the original block then you wouldn't want to split it
你就不会想拆分它
Because you would just keep it unsplit and then
你就会保持它不分裂
When you freed it then you'd have a block that would be the right size for that future request
当你释放它时，你将拥有一个适合未来请求的块
And so it's you can absolutely benefit from that
所以你绝对可以从中受益
And so although if general-purpose allocators there's no provision for that kind of hinting
因此，尽管通用分配器不能提供这种暗示
But there's nothing to prevent an allocator from doing predictions based on the previous pattern of requests
但是没有什么能阻止分配器根据先前的请求模式进行预测
You know so if you're getting a pattern of requests it's alternating large block,small block,large box,small block
你知道如果你得到一个请求模式 —— 大块，小块，大块，小块交替
You could exploit that maybe predict that the next request will be for...
你可以利用它可能预测下一个请求将是...
You know if the previous request is for a large block the next one might be for a small block and you could
如果前一个请求是针对一个大块的，那么下一个请求可能是一个小块
That's good question any other questions wizard yes
这是一个很好的问题，任何其他问题
I don't know
我不知道
So the question is other intelligent allocators that do that kind of prediction
所以问题是进行这种预测的其他智能分配器
And if there are I don't know of them,but I wouldn't I wouldn't say no
如果有我不知道他们，但我不会说不
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh well so the question is what if you ended up with a free block
哦，那么问题就是如果你最终得到了一个空闲区块
That's a single block surrounded by 2 allocated blocks
这是被 2 个已分配块包围块
Well in fact I mean that's one of the invariants that a good allocate has to maintain
事实上，我的意思是，这是一个好的分配必须保持的不变量之一
You should never have 2 contiguous free blocks
你永远不应该有  2 个连续的空闲块
Right the allocate should always be coalescing as much as it can
对分配应始终尽可能合并
And if it does that coalescing
如果它做到那个合并
If it always does that coalescing then there will never be two contiguous free blocks okay
如果它总是那样合并那么就永远不会有两个连续的空闲块
Yeah it's question
是的，问题？
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh you'll see when it comes into play when we free a block
哦，当我们释放一块时，你会看到它会发挥作用
Because you have to sort of stitch up
因为你必须要缝合
When you free a block you have to sort of stitch up the linked list and
当你释放一个块时，你必须对链接列表进行拼接
So you need both you need both pointers
所以你需要两个指针
You can do it with singly linked lists
你可以使用单链表进行此操作
So in your in the k in our book,there's a an allocate that uses a singly linked list
所以在我们书中，有一个使用单链表的分配
But the disadvantages that free requires a search
它的缺点是，调用 free 的时候需要搜索
So it requires a search from the beginning of the list to find the previous block
所以它需要从列表的开头搜索才能找到前一个块
And there are questions these are good yes question
有问题这些都是好问题
[student speaking]
学生提问
Okay so the question is for memory utilization
好的，问题是内存利用率
How does the header and footer count towards memory utilization
头部和脚部如何计入内存利用率
And so those are overhead  that decrease memory utilization
这些开销会降低内存利用率
Okay because they're not payload so when we were computing memory utilization
因为当我们计算内存利用率时，它们不是有效负载
We're doing it by we're using the payload the aggregate payload to
我们正在通过使用聚集有效载荷
To estimate utilization or to compute our utilization
来估算利用率或计算我们的利用率
So anything that's not payload sorry is overhead
所以任何不是有效载荷的东西都是开销
[student speaking]
学生提问
So we had...if all of payloads were one word and overhead
如果所有有效载荷都是一个，开销也是一个字
Was one word then there'd be 50%
那么利用率就是 50％
Yes [student speaking]
学生提问
Yeah so the question is do you still need a boundary tag if you have
是的，问题是你是否还需要一个边界标签
These next and previous pointers and the answer is yes absolutely
如果有这些指向下一个和前一个指针，答案绝对是肯定的
And you'll see in a second why
你会马上到原因
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Okay that's a really good question
好的，这是一个非常好的问题
So you know what do you do if you have next in previous pointers
如果你有指向前一个或者后一个的指针，你会怎么做
What happened if there's a request for a smaller block
如果要求更小的块，会发生什么
So the answer is that all of those things the header,the footer,the next and previous pointers
所以答案是所有这些东西的头部，脚部，下一个和前一个指针
Impose a minimum block size
施加最小块大小
So if you have a one word header,one word footer,one prev ,one word next
因此，如果你有一个字大小头部，一字大小脚部，一字大小下一个、上一个指针
Then your minimum block sizes is 4 bytes
然后你的最小块大小为 4 个字节
And that would be with a zero size payload
这将是零大小的有效载荷
So you can never allocate a block smaller than your minimum block size
因此，你永远不能分配小于最小块大小的块
So that's very good very good question
所以这是一个非常好的问题
So it makes a difference right even though
所以尽管如此，它确实有所作为
It looks like we're getting these pointers here for free
看起来这些指针是用来调用 free
But we're not really because of this minimum block size requirement
但我们不是，因为这个最小的块大小要求
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Yeah okay so...
是的，好吧......
The question is can you just get one large block and then split it up
问题是你可以得到一个大块然后将其拆分
And I guess you're assuming that the request would be 4 equally sized objects
而且我猜你假设这个请求是 4 个大小相同的对象
And that's a really good strategy actually
这实际上是一个非常好的策略
So if you think that your workload is going to have
因此，如果你认为你的工作量会有所增加
No you can't do this in general-purpose allocators
不，你不能在通用分配器中这样做
But for like a special-purpose allocator
但对于像专用分配器一样
If you know that you're going to be asking for objects that are all the same size
如果你知道你将要求大小相同的块
Like compilers for example may maintain abstract syntax trees
例如编译器可以维护抽象语法树
And and they're allocating nodes dynamically and those nodes are the same size
并且他们正在动态分配节点，并且这些节点的大小相同
So if you can exploit that by just allocating a large chunk
所以如果你可以通过分配一个大块来利用它
And then allocating all the objects of that size out of that chunk
然后从该块中分配该大小的所有对象
It's very efficient,you don't even need pointers or anything all you need is a bit vector
这是非常有效的，你甚至不需要指针或任何你需要的东西是有位向量
To tell you which chunks are allocated in which chunks are free
告诉你哪些块被分配在哪些块是空闲的
And then and you also has a side effect you'll get that contiguous
然后，你也有一个副作用
That contiguous access so if a program access those objects like
你会得到连续的访问，所以如果一个程序访问那些对象
To be part of a linked list there was something that it was going to traverse
要成为链接列表的一部分，它将会遍历某些内容
You could allocate those in order and contiguously
你可以按顺序和连续分配这些
Now with a general-purpose allocator where you don't really know
现在有一个通用的分配器，你真的不知道
What's going to be requested that
有什么样子的请求
[student speaking]
学生提问
Absolutely you could do that,you can make general assumptions about the  sort of behavior of your programs
绝对可以这样做，你可以对程序的行为进行一般性的假设
And you know you could run traces or like in the case of malloc lab you could look at the traces
并且你知道你可以在 malloc 实验室的情况下运行跟踪或类似的东西，你可以看看记录
But that's no that's a really good thing you know you can't
但这是很好的事情
You know you can't just like do if statements to say well
你知道你不能只是喜欢描述得好
If the size is 42 and then the next size is 24 then I know it's this trace
如果大小是 42 然后下一个大小是 24，那么我知道这是一个记录
But you can look at a trace and say whom there's an interesting pattern here
但是你可以看一下这个记录，并说出这里有一个有趣的模式
I'm going to account for that pattern I'm going to optimize for that pattern
我将考虑针对该模式进行优化
And that would just and that's perfectly valid that's just like taking advantage of
这就是公正和完全有效的，就像利用它一样
Your workload right that's what we do in systems all the time
你的工作是我们在系统中始终做的事情
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh oh so the question is why can't we...
哦，哦，问题是为什么我们不能......
Why can't we sort of have separate areas of the heap for the pointers  and the payloads all right
为什么我们不能为指针和有效负载分别拥有堆的独立区域
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh so the question is why not,why can't we split up payloads
哦，好的，问题是为什么我们不能拆分有效载荷
And link them together with pointers
并用指针将它们链接在一起
The answer is that the applications expecting a contiguous block
答案是应用程序期望一个连续的块
You can't allocate or can't put anything in the payload
你无法分配或无法在有效负载中放置任何内容
Right all it's allowed to do is return a contiguous block of the size of the application requested
所允许做的就是返回一个与所请求的应用程序大小相连的块
And app once it does that it can't touch it okay
应用程序一旦它这样做它不能触摸它
All right good good
好的好
All right so let's look at how we'd allocate and free
好的，让我们来看看我们如何分配和释放
Once if we have this explicit list how we would allocate and free blocks
如果我们有这个显式列表，我们将如何分配和释放块
So allocating is pretty simple
所以分配非常简单
So here's our sort of a graphic of a free list
这里是我们的空闲列表图形
So we have 4 word pointers and backward pointers
所以我们有 4 字大小得指针和后向指针
And the idea is we want to allocate out of this middle block
我们想要分配出这个中间块
So
所以
We allocate the block of the size that we need
我们分配了我们需要的大小的块
And then we just update the forward and back pointers of the previous and next blocks
然后我们只更新前一个和下一个块的前向和后向指针
To point to this new free block
指向这个新的空闲区块
Okay so that's pretty simple we're just updating 6 pointers
好的，这很简单，我们只是更新 6 个指针
Okay now it gets trickier when we have to free because
当我们释放得时候，事情变得更加棘手
Because we require coalescing
因为我们需要合并
So when you free a block
所以当你释放一块时
That's that was previously allocated
那是之前分配的
The question is what do you do with that free block right it wasn't in the free list
问题是你如何处理这个空闲区块，它不在空闲列表中
Because it was an allocated block
因为它是一个已分配的块
So now that you've freed the block where do you put it
所以现在你已经释放了阻止你把它放在哪里
Which you've got to put it somewhere
你必须把它放在某个地方
So that the simplest thing is this lifo policy
所以最简单的事就是这个「LIFO 政策」
So the simplest thing is just put it at the beginning of the list
所以最简单的事就是把它放在列表的开头
So the last block freed is the first block allocated if it fits
因此，释放的最后一个块是分配的第一个块（如果它适合）
Okay so that's so-called LIFO
那就是所谓的 LIFO
Now this is simple
现在这很简单
Because you're always doing the same thing you're just putting the block at the beginning the list
因为你总是在做同样的事情，你只是将块放在列表的开头
And it's constant time you're just updating a few pointers
而且你只需要更新几个指针就可以了
Okay but the studies suggest that the fragmentation can be worse than the alternative technique
好的，但研究表明碎片可能比替代技术更糟糕
Which is to keep the blocks ordered by address
这是保持按地址排序的块
Okay so why not if you choose this address ordered policy when you when you free an allocated block
好的，那么为什么不在你释放分配的块时选择这个地址排序策略
You're going to somehow figure out,you're going to somehow place that block in the list
你会以某种方式将该块放在列表中
So that the previous block begins at a smaller address
这样前一个块就从一个较小的地址开始
And the next block begins at a larger address
下一个块从更大的地址开始
Right so this generally involves some kind of search
所以这通常涉及某种搜索
You're just given this allocated block
你只是给了这个分配块
And then somehow you've got and you know it's address
然后以某种方式你得到了它的地址
And so now you've got to somehow search the free list
所以现在你必须以某种方式搜索空闲列表
To find the you know the proper place to insert it
找到插入它的适当位置
Now I suppose you could do better if you had some kind of...
现在我想如果你有某种方法你可以做得更好
So if you could speed up that search with some kind of  balance tree that would be one option
因此，如果你可以使用某种平衡树加速搜索，这将是一种选择
Right but then the problem we always run into with balance trees and
但后来问题我们总是遇到平衡树和
Usually one student...
通常一个学生......
Somebody always tries to implement malloc with some kind of balance tree red-black tree or something
有人总是试图用某种平衡树红黑树或其他东西来实现 malloc
And it seems like a really good idea
这似乎是一个非常好的主意
But you have to realize that you're competing with other techniques specifically segregated lists
但是你必须意识到你正在与其他技术竞争，特别是隔离列表
That are very fast,they have very small constant factors
这非常快，它们具有非常小的常数因子
And there's even though ordered lists are I think
我认为即使有序列表也是如此
It's usually nlog(n) to update an order tree a binary ordered tree
通常使用 nlog(n) 更新二叉有序树
The constant factors can be quite large
常数因素可能非常大
And so usually get nailed up with the constant factors of maintaining the tree
因此通常会坚持使用维护树的常数因素
And you don't get help that the search time is log(n)
你没有得到搜索时间为 log(n) 的帮助
But as we'll see with segregated lists
但正如我们将看到的隔离列表
In the limit as the number of different size classes increases
在限制中随着不同大小类的数量增加
The search time approaches constant time
搜索时间接近恒定时间
And if you have size classes that cover ranges of powers of two
如果你有包含不同范围的大小
Then the search time reduces to log time anyway
然后搜索时间减少到「logn」时间
Because the size of each classes are now logarithmic the log
因为每个大小得类现在都是对数的
So you know I would suggest on
所以你知道我会建议
You know just doing the simple thing usually whenever you're dealt with
通常当你处理像 malloc 这样得大型得空间设计得时候
Sort of large design space like malloc it's you're better off doing the simple thing
你最好只做一些简单的事情
And then optimizing only when you see that there's that you need to optimize
然后只有当你发现需要优化时才进行优化
Okay so remember last time we talked about this trick to eliminate the boundary tag footer and allocated blocks
好的，所以记得上次我们谈到这个技巧来消除边界标签脚部和分配块
That's an example of an optimization you should defer
这是你应该推迟的优化的一个例子
So that wait you know wait get, do the simple thing and then try to improve incrementally by
做一些简单的事情，然后尝试逐步改进
By you know this optimization or another optimization
通过你了解此优化或其他优化
So there's this phenomena of a lot of programmers make the mistake of what we call premature optimization
所以很多程序员都会犯这种现象，我们称之为过早优化
So try to think of all the fancy things they can do
所以试着想想他们能做的所有奇特的事情
And then they put all those in at the beginning
然后他们把所有这些都放在了开头
And before they even know that it needs to be optimized
在他们甚至知道它需要优化之前
Okay so the sort of the way you want to work on this and any sort of complex
好的，那就是你想要解决这个问题的方式以及任何类型的复杂问题
Problem like an allocate
问题就像分配一样
Is to you know first do fairly simple things and then look and see where
是你知道先做相当简单的事情
Where the slowdowns are and inefficiencies are and then just sort of
然后看看哪里很慢，哪里效率很低
Hit those one after the other and optimize only for the things that are necessary
然后一个接一个地击中那些并且仅针对必要的事物进行优化
And this is a good example of that
这是一个很好的例子
Okay now to get to your question about freeing
现在好了解你关于释放的问题
Freeing is tough because we always have to do this coalescing right
解放是困难的，因为我们总是必须正确地进行合并
Because of this invariant that we can never have to free blocks  to adjacent free blocks
由于这种不变性，我们永远不能将块释放到相邻的空闲块
So let's go through each of those 4 cases that we went over last time
那么让我们来看看上次我们去过的 4  个案例
And see how we would do it
看看我们将如何做到这一点
Now that we have this explicit free list
现在我们有了这个显式空闲列表
So here we have the root of a free list
所以这里我们有一个空闲列表的根
Pointing to the first block in the free list
指向空闲列表中的第一个块
There's an all back pointer and then that
有一个指向后面得指针
There's a null pointer and then the next pointer points to some unspecified block
有一个空指针，然后下一个指针指向一些未指定的块
And so we have this yellow block which is allocated
所以我们有这个分配的黄色块
And now the application is called free, free with a pointer that points to the beginning of this block
现在，应用程序调用 free，释放其指针指向此块的开头
So what do we do
那么我们该怎么办
Well this case is pretty simple because there's no coalescing
那么这个案子非常简单，因为没有合并
Because both the predecessor and successor blocks are allocated
因为前驱块和后继块都已分配
Okay so we just this newly freed block now becomes we're going to do a LIFO policy
好的，所以我们这个刚刚释放的块，现我们要做的 LIFO 政策
So this becomes the first block in the free list
所以这成为空闲列表中的第一个块
And so we update the root to point to this
所以我们更新根指向这个新释放得块
This newly freed block and we update the forward pointer of that block to point to what used to be the first block in the heap
我们更新该块的前向指针，此指向曾经是堆中第一个块的内容
Now I'm going to be careful
现在我要小心了
It's a little bit confusing
这有点令人困惑
Because we've got sort of two notions of like previous and next right there's the
因为我们有两个像前一个和下一个一样的概念
You know given some block
已知一些块
There's the predecessor block in memory which may or may not be allocated or free right
内存中的前一个块可能会被分配了或者可能是空闲的
It may or may not be in a free list
它可能在也可能不在空闲列表中
And there's a successor block
还有一个后继块
Okay so we'll use predecessor and successor to distinguish adjacency in memory
好的，我们将使用前驱和后继来区分内存中的邻接块
Okay and we'll use pre even next to denote adjacency in the free list
好的，我们将使用前一个和后一个表示空闲列表中的邻接
Okay so this block is the next block for the current block
好的，所以这个块是当前块的下一个块
And it has no previous block okay
它没有前一个块
All right now what about case 2,remember case 2 the predecessor block is free
那么现在怎么样的情况 2，记住案例 2 前驱块是空闲的
And the successor block is allocated
并且继承块被分配
And now we want to free this
现在我们要释放这个
What was an allocated block denoted by yellow
黄色表示的分配块
And we have this predecessor block is part of the free list
这个前驱块是空闲列表的一部分
Right so it has previous and next blocks
对，所以它有前一个和下一个块
That are just part of the free list
这只是空闲清单的一部分
And so a route points just the first block in the list and then eventually
因此，路线仅指向列表中的第一个块，然后最终指向
You get to this free block which points to this free block which points to this free block
你到达这个空闲区块，指向这个空闲区块，指向这个空闲块
Ok so what we have to do then
那么我们必须做什么呢
Is we have to coalesce these two blocks into one big free block
我们是否必须将这两个区块合并成一个大的自由区块
Okay and then we have to splice it out and stick it at the beginning of the list
好的，然后我们必须将它拼接出来并将其放在列表的开头
Ok so what that looks like conceptually is we...
那么在概念上看起来就是
We coalesce these two blocks now to form this one free block
我们现在合并这两个块以形成这个一个空闲块
And then we splice it out by
然后我们将它拼接出来
Having what was its previous block now point to what used to be the next block
拥有它以前的块现在指向过去的下一个块
Okay of the current block
好的当前块
Okay so this
好的，所以这个
The pointer from this block now points to this block
此块的指针现在指向此块
Okay and then the so we've effectively spliced that current block out of the free list
好的，然后我们已经有效地将当前的块拼成空闲列表
And then we have the route point to that block
然后我们有指向这个块的路线
So that's now the new first block of the list
所以现在是列表中新的第一个块
Okay and then we have to update what used to be the first block in the list
好的，然后我们必须更新以前列表中的第一个块
So now it points back to the newly freed coalesced block
所以现在它指向新释放的合并块
So that cleared everybody it yes
所有人都清楚了吗？
Would it be a global variable it could be or it could be
因此，可以是全局变量，也可以是
There's two ways to do this right it could just be a global variable
有两种方法可以做到这一点，它可能只是一个全局变量
Or it could be a struct that of like previous and next pointer
或者它可能是一个类似上一个和下一个指针的结构
So sometimes it's easier if you keep the same you know when you're doing a linked list that
因此，如果你在做链接列表的时候保持相同的话，有时会更容易
The route if you just make it the same as all the other nodes it can simplify things
如果你只是将其与所有其他节点相同，则可以简化操作
But yeah it could be a global variable,global scalar in the allocator
它可能是一个全局变量，分配器中的全局标量
Okay so case...oh now one thing one thing that comes to mind there is like
现在有一件事情可以想到就像是
There is an optimization that we could do
我们可以做一个优化
In this case do you see when we coalesce
在这种情况下，你看到我们何时合并
We could just lead that block right there in the free list
我们可以在空闲列表中直接引导该块到此处
Right we didn't although we've adopted
对，我们没有
So the examples I'm going to show you are assuming a LIFO policy for insertion
因此，我将向你展示的示例是假设插入的 LIFO 策略
We could just leave it there right that and just don't update anything
我们可以把它留在那里，只是不更新​​任何东西
Just increase create this newly coalesce block
只需增加创建这个新的合并块
In this case we wouldn't require any free list manipulation
在这种情况下，我们不需要任何空闲列表操作
Okay but that would be that would be one of these optimizations right
好的，但那将是这些优化之一
That now
那就是现在
Case 3 if you recall is the case where the the predecessor block is allocated
如果你还记得案例 3 是分配了前驱块的情况
And the successor block is free
后继块是空闲的
The successor block is free
So in this case what we have to do is we have to create
所以在这种情况下我们要做的就是创造
We have to coalesce the newly freed block with the successor block
我们必须将新释放的块与后继块合并
And then we have to splice it out in just the same way we did in case 2
然后我们必须以与案例 2 中相同的方式将其拼接出来
So we splice it out of the list
所以我们将它拼接出列表
And then put it at the beginning of the list by pointing the root at it
然后通过将根指向它来将其放在列表的开头
And then updating what used to be the first block in the list
然后更新曾经是列表中第一个块的内容
Updating its back pointer it's pre pointer to point to the newly coalesced block
更新其后向指针，它的前向指针指向新合并的块
Okay so this is completely symmetric with the case that we looked at before
好的，这与我们之前看过的情况完全对称
But now we no longer have
但现在我们不再拥有
It's a little bit trickier if we just wanted to leave this block in the free list
如果我们只想将这个块留在空闲列表中，这有点棘手
We'd have to update all these pointers to point back
我们必须更新所有这些指针以指回
To the beginning of the newly created block
到新创建的块的开头
Okay so there's
好的，那就是
So in this case there's no performance
所以在这种情况下没有好的性能优化
Optimization right we're still updating the same number of pointers
我们仍在更新相同数量的指针
Whether we put it in the beginning of the list
我们是否把它放在列表的开头
Or if we splice it or if we leave it there
或者如果我们拼接它或者我们把它留在那里
And now case 4 is the
而现在案例 4 就是
That's the case where both the predecessor and successor blocks are free
这是前驱和后继块都是空闲的情况
So we have to apply the same splicing technique to both the predecessor block
因此，我们必须将相同的拼接技术应用于前一个块
And we have to create this new coalesced block
我们必须创建这个新的合并块
And then we have to splice
然后我们必须拼接
We have to we have to sort of splice it out by updating
我们必须通过更新两组不同的前驱和后继块
Two different sets of previous and successor blocks
来解决这个问题
So when we're finished with that
所以当我们完成那个
That the this newly coalesced block now is the first block in the heap
现在这个新合并的块是堆中的第一个块
In the free list
在空闲列表中
And we've spliced it,we splice it out from these two different parts of the of the free list
我们拼接了它，我们将它从空闲列表的这两个不同部分拼接出来
Okay so any questions about
好的，所以有任何疑问
It looks it looks really simple to do
看起来它看起来很简单
But I guarantee you this will be
但我保证
Some the hardest
对于有些人，这里是最难的
It's only like 200 lines of code
它只有 200 行代码
But some of the hardest code you'll have to write because
但是你必须编写一些最难的代码，因为
You're sort of free of the c's types us that you have to do everything by explicitly casting
你必须通过显式的代码来做所有事情
These pointers are just in the middle of arbitrary blocks
这些指针位于任意块的中间
So it looks simple with the diagram but you're going to have to be really careful when you do this
因此，图表看起来很简单，但是当你这样做时你必须要非常小心
In fact what I would suggest the
事实上我会建议的
Best suggestion I can give you is
我能给你的最佳建议是
If is to start with the implicit list allocator
如果是从隐式列表分配器开始
That we describe in the book which is too slow to get any credit
我们在书中描述的那个太慢而无法获得任何功劳
It's a terrible allocator
这是一个糟糕的分配器
But it contains all the basic ideas
但它包含了所有基本思想
And then write function write a function called insert block and write another function called remove block
然后写函数写一个名为「insert block」的函数，并编写另一个名为「remove block」的函数
That inserts a block into the free list and removes a block from the free list respectively
将块插入空闲列表并分别从空闲列表中删除块
And if you write, if you abstract it like that
如果你写，如果你这样抽象
If you use that kind of abstraction it's pretty simple
如果使用这种抽象，那就非常简单了
To convert the implicit list allocator to an explicit list allocator
将隐式列表分配器转换为显式列表分配器
It'll still be too slow to get
得到它仍然太慢了
So then that'll go from like a f allocator to a b-allocator
那么那将会像 F 等级的分配器变成一个 B- 等级的分配器一样
And then to really make a good allocator like an a allocator you need to use segregated lists
然后真正做一个像分配器一样好的分配器，你需要使用隔离列表
Which we'll look at in a second
我们马上就能看到
Okay so the explicit lists
好的，所以显式列表
Now the allocation time is linear in the number of free blocks instead of the total size
现在，分配时间是空闲块的数量呈线性关系
Of the instead of the total size of the heap
而不是堆的总大小
So it's this is much faster than that when you have a lot of allocated blocks
所以这比你拥有大量分配的块要快得多
It's a little more complicated because of all the splicing business
由于所有的需要拼接，它有点复杂
And you do need some extra space in your
你确实需要一些额外的空间
For these pointers which increases the minimum block size
由于这些增加最小块大小的指针
And creates additional and overhead
并创造额外的和开销
Now the link list the explicit list allocators aren't really
显式列表分配器
Efficient enough to be used for sort of general purpose real-life allocator
不是足够高效地用于各种通用于现实生活分配器
But they are useful in as part of a segregated list allocator
但它们作为隔离列表分配器的一部分很有用
So you can have multiple free lists each of which is an explicit list
所以你可以拥有多个空闲列表，每个列表都是一个显式列表
And this it's fine for that application
这对于该应用程序来说很好
Alright so let's look at a third method which is to create call a segregated free list
好吧，让我们看看第三种方法，即创建一个隔离的空闲列表
Which is to have multiple free lists with different size classes
这是多个具有不同大小类的空闲列表
So the idea is that each
所以想法是
Each class of sizes
每类尺寸
Block sizes has its own free list
块大小有自己的空闲列表
And that class can be singleton so you know maybe a one particular size
那个类可以是单身，所以你知道可能是一个特定的大小
Or it can be a range of sizes
或者它可以是一系列尺寸
So you might have a number of different
所以你可能会有很多不同的东西
You know if your workload consists of a lot of these small blocks
你知道你的工作量是否包含很多这些小块
And you know that there's going to be a lot of requests for blocks
而且你知道会有很多块请求
Of 1 through 4
其大小是 1 到 4
You can have different free lists for those small for those small block sizes
对于那些小块大小，你可以拥有不同的空闲列表
And then after that you can go and just do ranges of power of two
然后你可以标定一些范围
So that's  a common technique
所以这是一种常见的技术
So here we have a size class that covers blocks from size 5 to 8
所以这里我们有一个大小类，涵盖从 5 到 8 的块
And then the another size class that covers everything else
然后是另一个涵盖其他一切的大小类
So the idea with the seglist allocators that
所以用 seglist 分配器的想法就是这样
So given an array of these free lists one each one for some size class
因此给出了这些空闲列表的数组，每个列表都有一个大小类
If we want to allocate a block of size n
如果我们想要分配一个大小为 n  的块
Then we go to the appropriate free list
然后我们去相应的空闲列表
Right there's only,there's always going to be one free list for any n
对于任何 n，其中总会有一个块大小为 n 的空闲列表
And then we search that list just like we did before
然后我们像以前一样搜索该列表
For some size at a block size m > n
对于块大小 m > n 的某些大小
And then if we find it then we place
然后，如果我们找到它
We place the new block
我们放置新块
We place the block in the block that we found
我们将块放在我们找到的块中
We split it
我们分开了
And we take this split block and we put it into the appropriate size class
我们采用这个拆分块，然后将它放入适当的大小类中
So that the block that we split off
这样我们拆分的块
May or may not belong to the current size class anymore
可能会或可能不会属于当前的大小等级
Right so we may have to move it and insert it into a whatever the appropriate size class is
所以我们可能必须移动它并将其插入任何适当的大小类
If there's no block if we can't find a block
如果我们找不到块
Then we have to try the next larger size class
然后我们必须尝试下一个更大的类
Okay so it's possible for a given size class
好的，对于给定的大小
They're just there might not be a block that fits
可能没有适合的块
So I mean one so we just have to we go to the next size
所以我们只需要进入下一个尺寸
We try the next larger class and chances are we'll find a block that fits there
我们尝试下一个更大的尺寸，我们很有可能在那找到一个适合块
And if we and you keep doing that until you eventually if you can't find it
如果我们和你一直这样做，直到你最终如果你找不到它
You're eventually looking in the size class that covers all the rest the last size class
你最终会查看覆盖所有其余大小类的大小类
And if then you can't find it then that the allocator has to allocate more memory with by calling sbreak
如果那时你找不到它，那么分配器必须通过调用 sbreak 来分配更多的内存
Okay to free a block you coalesce like before
好吧，像以前一样合并一块
And then you place it on the appropriate list
之后将其放在适当的列表中
So that's straightforward and again you have this option to try to maintain a listed
所以这很简单，你再次尝试维护一个列出的选项
Address order or just do the simple thing and put it at the beginning of the list
地址顺序或只做简单的事情 —— 将其放在列表的开头
Okay so seglist allocator are that by far the best type of allocator
所以 seglist 分配器是迄今为止最好的分配器类型
Because they offer you improvements in both performance throughput and memory utilization
因为它们为你提供了吞吐量上的进步和内存利用率方面的改进
So they're faster they have higher throughputs because the
所以他们的速度更快，具有更高的吞吐量
The individual size classes are smaller
因为区别一一个巨大的空闲清单
Then just like the one giant free list
它的单个的大小更小
But also you're searching
但你也在寻找
You're you know that the list that you're searching
你正在搜索的列表
Is going to be close to the size that you're looking for so the chances of finding something quickly
将接近你正在寻找的大小，以便快速找到某些东西
In that particular size class are higher than they are
在那个特定的尺寸的列表搜索会更快
If you're just searching
相较于在寻找
On you know a single free list that holds all different size classes
一个包含所有不同大小类的空闲列表
Okay so search is faster so that increases increases throughput
好的，所以搜索更快，以便增加吞吐量
But the big thing about seglist allocator is that
但是关于 Seglist 分配器的重要一点是
Like we talked about before they approximate best fit without sacrificing performance
就像我们之前谈到的那样，它们在不牺牲性能的情况下接近最佳匹配
Right before if we wanted to do best fit on a single a free list
如果我们想要在一个空闲列表中做到最合适，就在此之前
We had to search the whole free list
我们不得不搜索整个空闲列表
And then choose the block that fit the best
然后选择最适合的块
In this case we get best fit for free
在这种情况下，我们最适合空闲块
By by virtue of having these size classes
由于具有这些尺寸等级
And so this is
所以这就是
You know this is how you can improve your memory utilization
你知道这是如何提高内存利用率的方法
Yes
是
[student speaking]
学生提问
Oh yeah yeah good question
哦，是的好问题
So the question is break constant time
所以问题是是打破常数时间
It is but it's very expensive
这是非常昂贵的
So it's a syscall so it has to pass from user space into the kernel that involves
所以它是一个系统调用，所以它必须从用户空间传递到内核
Changing contacts changing stacks
更改调用人更改堆栈
So syscalls
系统调用
Generally you can count on syscall being like several hundred microseconds
一般来说，你可以指望系统调用几百微秒
Okay it's a non-trivial overhead
但这是一个非常大的开销
And so in that case you wouldn't want
所以在这种情况下
You want to amortize the cost of the break
你要分摊中断的开销
By allocating is somewhat larger chunk
通过分配是一个更大的块
But you have to be careful if you allocate too large of a chunk then your memory utilization goes down
但是如果分配太大的块然后你的内存利用率下降，你必须要小心
So it's a trade-off,it's another one of these space-time trade-offs
所以这是一个权衡，这是另一个时空权衡
Question
请讲
[student speaking]
学生提问
So where do you store this array of free lists
那么你在哪里存储这个空闲列表数组
So you store it in the beginning of the heap
所以你将它存储在堆的开头
Yeah in fact for your malloc lab we require you to do that
事实上，对于你的 malloc lab，我们要求你这样做
We don't know
我们不知道
And the reason is we can't
原因是我们做不到
That array affects in some small part
该阵列在一些小部分中受到影响
Depending on how large that array is it affects your memory utilization
取决于该阵列的大小，它会影响你的内存利用率
And so it should be at the beginning of the heap
所以它应该在堆的开头
Okay there's an allocators have been around forever and
好的，分配器已经永远存在了
That the the classic references can use 1973 text
经典参考文献可以追溯到 1973
And there's also this great paper which you can get from the books website
还有这篇很棒的论文，你可以从书籍网站上获得
From 1995 that does a survey of
从 1995 年开始进行调查
You know literate dozens and dozens of techniques like
你知道有数十种技术
We're just scratching the surface here
我们只是在这里摸索表面
So if you're really interested in this stuff
所以如果你真的对这些东西感兴趣的话
That is that papers a fascinating read
那篇文章引人入胜
And it may give you some ideas for your free lab
它可能会为你的 free lab 提供一些想法
Ok now so far
好了，到目前为止
We're assuming that the application is responsible for both allocating storage and freeing storage
我们假设应用程序负责分配存储和释放存储
But there's a form of memory managers called implicit memory managers
但是有一种称为隐式内存管理器的内存管理器
That do the freeing for you
它帮助你完成释放
So applications allocate space
应用程序分配空间
But they never have to worry about freeing space the system does that automatically
但他们永远不必担心释放空间，系统会自动释放空间
And so the idea is to identify so-called garbage
因此，想法是识别所谓的垃圾
So areas of memory that can never be referenced anymore
所以永远不能再引用的内存区域
And then free up those blocks
然后释放那些块
Okay so what's garbage well here's an example we have a function foo  that malloc 128 bytes
那有什么垃圾？举个例子，我们有一个函数 foo 里面使用 malloc 分配了 128 字节
It stores the address in this pointer p
它将地址存储在该指针 p 中
And then at some point when it returns from foo
然后返回
This pointer is lost forever right because p is a local variable on the stack
这个指针永远丢失，因为 p 是堆栈上的局部变量
So once this function returns
一旦这个函数返回
That the block of memory pointed to by p is garbage can never be referenced again
p 指向的内存块是垃圾，永远不能再被引用
Because there's no way,there's no way for the program to get get access to that
因为没有办法，程序无法获得访问权限
And so what an allocator will recognize
那么分配器会识别什么
At some point that this block of memory is garbage
在某些时候，这块内存是垃圾
And that it will free those blocks by calling free
并且它将通过调用 free 来释放这些块
It's the same kind of exactly the same free call
调用的是相同的 free 函数
As we've discussed
正如我们所讨论的那样
But now it's called by the garbage collector not by the application
但现在它被垃圾收集器调用而不是应用程序
Okay so you see this in all different kinds of dynamic languages
好吧，你可以在所有不同类型的动态语言中看到这一点
And there's there's there's also variants available for C
而且还有可用于 C 的变体
But because of C's pointer properties
但是因为 C 的指针属性
That the garbage collectors for C are conservative in the sense
从某种意义上说，C 的垃圾收集器是保守的
That there's some blocks won't be freed
有一些块将不会被释放
There's some garbage blocks that won't be free
有些垃圾块不会释放
Because the allocator can't determine that they are indeed garbage
因为分配器无法确定它们是垃圾
So it has to be careful when it whenever there's a doubt
因此，只要有疑问，就必须小心
It it leaves it doesn't reclaim the allocated block
所以不会回收这些分配的块
So it gets to this question of like how does the memory manager know when memory can be free
所以有这样一个问题，内存管理器如何知道内存何时可以被释放
And you know if we knew
而且
If somehow we knew we could predict all of the future requests
如果以某种方式我们知道我们可以预测所有未来的请求
And then if we knew that there were no future requests access that block then we could free it
然后，如果我们知道将来没有请求访问该块，那么我们可以释放它
Okay but we can't predict that
好的，但我们无法预测
Okay so we have to
所以我们可以......
But if there's no pointers
但如果没有指针
If no pointers exist to a particular block then we know that it can't be accessed
如果特定块没有指针，那么我们就知道无法访问它
Okay and so that we can predict right if there's some way
好的，以便我们可以预测是否有某种方式
We can sort of scan the program identify or scan the memory identify all the pointers in that memory
我们可以扫描程序识别或扫描内存识别该内存中的所有指针
And and see which blocks are pointed to
并查看指向哪些块
And if they're not pointed to by any pointer than then they're garbage by definition
如果它们没有被任何指针指向，那么根据定义它们就是垃圾
Okay so to do this though it's difficult
好的，这样做虽然很难
So first of all the memory manager has to be able to distinguish pointers from non pointers
首先，内存管理器必须能够区分指针和非指针
Which we can't do and see right they're just these integral values
我们做不到，他们只是一个值
Right we don't know it could be it
我们不知道它是不是指针
If we see this large integral value
如果我们看到这个大值
This large long a 8 byte value
这个大的长 8 字节值
It could be pointing to a data structure it could just be a large integer right
它可能指向一个数据结构，它可能只是一个大整数
We don't know
我们不知道
And then we also all pointers have to point to the start of a block which is not true and see either
然后我们所有指针都必须指向一个的块的开始，这个我们也看不到
Okay so if we have a pointer and we identify that it's a pointer
好的，如果我们有一个指针，我们发现它是一个指针
Then we know that it points to some block
然后我们知道它指向一些块
If it points inside of a block how do we how do we find the beginning of that block
如果它指向一个块的内部，我们如何找到该块的开头
You know how do we know how big that block is
你知道我们怎么知道那个块有多大
All right so it has to point to the beginning of the block where the header  tells us the size and
所以它必须指向块的开头，头部告诉我们块大小
The and there can't be a way to hide pointers
并且没有办法隐藏指针
The point that the property of being a pointer has to be some kind of static
作为指针的属性必须是某种静态的点
Thing that doesn't that can't change
那不能改变的东西
So that's sort of the challenges
所以这就是挑战
If you're thinking about how in the world can you implement a garbage collector
如果你正在考虑究竟如何实现垃圾收集器
So those are some of the challenges that they present
所以这些是他们提出的一些挑战
And because of that this is this been a the history of research and garbage collectors is old
而正因为如此，这是研究它的历史，垃圾回收是一个非常古老问题
Its ancient and ongoing
它古老而持续
It's still it's still ongoing today particularly in the context of parallel programs
今天仍在继续研究，特别是在并行程序的背景下
And garbage collecting programs that are running multiple threads
程序运行多个线程进行垃圾回收
So there's a whole bunch of these things
所以这里有很多东西
That people have looked at going all the way back to 1960
人们研究它的历史能一直追溯到 1960 年
Today we'll look at we'll look at the simplest
今天我们来看看最简单的
What one of the simpler variants called mark-and-sweep
其中之一称为「标记和扫描」
And we won't discuss the rest
我们不会讨论其余的问题
But if you're interested in them there's a pretty good book that describes that describes these things
但是，如果你对它们感兴趣，有一本非常好的书介绍这些内容
All right so how do we build an allocator
好的，我们如何建立一个分配器
So we start by viewing memory as a directed graph
我们首先将内存视为有向图
Where each node in the graph corresponds to a block
图中的每个节点对应一个块
Okay a block a heap block
好吧一个堆块
And an allocated heap block
一个分配的堆块
And each edge is a pointer that's contained somewhere within that block
每个边都是一个包含在该块内某处的指针
Okay a pointer to another block
好的指向另一个块的指针
And then there's special nodes called root nodes
然后有一些称为根节点的特殊节点
That contain pointers into the heap but they're not part of the heap
它包含指向堆的指针，但它们不是堆的一部分
So for example pointers that are stored on the stack
例如存储在堆栈上的指针
Pointers that are stored in registers
存储在寄存器中的指针
They point to memory locations in the heap
它们指向堆中的内存位置
But nothing and but there outside of the heap
但除了堆外
So and we call those route notes
我们称这些路线结点
So nothing points to them or at least if something does point to them
所以没有任何东西指向他们，或者至少如果有什么东西指向他们
We don't care about what it is
我们不关心它是什么
Okay we're only concerned about characterizing nodes that correspond to memory in the heap
我们只关心表征与堆中的内存相对应的节点
So I we say that a a node or a block is reachable
所以我说我们可以访问一个节点或一个块
If there's some path from a root node
如果有一个来自根节点的路径
From a root node to that block
从根节点到该块
So and we've denoted those by green
所以我们用绿色表示了那些
So all of these green blocks in the heap are reachable
因此堆中的所有这些绿色块都是可访问的
Because you can start at a root node and just follow some sequence of pointers to get to that node
因为你可以从根节点开始，只需按照一些指针序列即可到达该节点
Nodes that aren't reachable are called a garbage
无法访问的结点称为垃圾
Because there's  no way to get to them from the root nodes
因为没有办法从根节点到达它们
Okay so there's no node inside the heap that points to them
好的，所以堆里面没有指向它们的节点
And there's no node, there's no root node that points to them
并且没有指向它们的根节点
So basically there's just no path from a root node
所以基本上没有来自根节点的路径
That'll get you to one of these non reachable or garbage nodes
使你进入这些不可达或垃圾节点之一
And since they're non reachable
因为他们无法到达
The application will never be able to reference them in the future
该应用程序将来永远无法引用它们
So we can predict with certainty
所以我们可以肯定地预测
That that those are garbage and they can be freed
那些是垃圾，它们可以被释放
So basically after we free these then they're removed from the graph
所以基本上在我们释放这些之后，它们就会从图表中删除
So now we can build
所以现在我们可以建立
A simple garbage collector on top of the existing malloc and free package
基于现有 malloc 和 free 软件包之上的简单垃圾收集器
Right so you implement malloc and free just like before
像以前一样实现 malloc 和 free
And then you the program
然后你的程序
Calls malloc just like before
像以前一样调用 malloc
And you just you do malloc exactly the same way until you run out of space
而且你只是以完全相同的方式做 malloc，直到你的空间不足为止
By whatever different definition you want to use of running out of space
通过任何不同的定义，你希望使空间不足
Maybe you have some kind of maximum heap size you're willing to use
也许你愿意使用的最大的堆
Or at some point the os will just stop giving you virtual memory
或者在某些时候，操作系统将停止为你提供虚拟内存
When you run out of space
当你的空间不足时
You add an extra mark bit into the header of each block
你在每个块的头部中添加一个额外的标记位
So this could be you know we have like 3 or 4 spare bits
所以这可能是你知道我们有 3 或 4 个备用位
That we can use in the header
我们可以在头部中使用
So we can denote one of those as the mark bit
所以我们可以将其中一个表示为标记位
And then we are garbage collection
然后我们是垃圾收集
Our garbage collection phase when we run out of space consists of two different sub phases
当我们用完空间时，我们的垃圾回收包括两个不同的子阶段
One is the mark phase which starts at all the roots
之一是从所有根节点开始的标记
And then and it just traverses this from the roots
然后它只是从根结点上穿过它
It traverses the set of of nodes
遍历所有节点
That are reachable from the root and it sets the mark bit in each one of those nodes
可从根访问，并在每个节点中设置标记位
Okay and then once after you finish marking all of the reachable blocks
好的，然后在完成标记所有可到达的块之后
Then you sweep through the entire heap starting at the very beginning of the heap
然后从堆的最开始扫描整个堆
And you look for all allocated blocks that aren't marked
并且查找未标记的所有已分配块
So they're not marked they're not reachable in their garbage
所以它们没有标记没有办法遍历到几点就是垃圾
So first, you do a search from the roots
首先，你从根节点开始搜索
And then you do a sweep of the entire heap
然后你扫描整个堆
So let's say before the marks
所以，在标记之前
We have a heap that looks like this,we have a single root that points to this block
我们有一个看起来像这样的堆，我们有一个指向这个块的根
And what we're going to do here we're always going to point to the payload right of the block
而我们在这里要做的就是总是指向块的有效载荷
It's just a convention that we use
这只是我们使用的惯例
So we're pointing to the beginning of the block
所以我们指的是块的开头
Because we know that the header is one word behind it
因为我们知道头部后是一个字
And so let's say and in this case
在这种情况下
The edges denote pointers that are contained in the block
边表示块中包含的指针
So they're not the previous and next pointers that we were maintaining
所以它们不是我们维护的上一个和下一个指针
These are just pointers that the application has put into those blocks
这些只是应用程序放入这些块的指针
So here we have the root pointing to this the central block
这里我们有根指向这个中心块
And then there's a pointer that points to this block
然后有一个指向这个块的指针
And there's another pointer that points to this block and
并且还有另一个指向此块的指针
And there's a pointer in this block that points to this block
并且此块中有一个指针指向此块
So after we do the mark
所以在我们做了标记之后
And we search this we search these and then
我们搜索这些之后
All of the reachable blocks have the mark bit set which is denoted by pink
所有可到达的块都具有标记位设置，其由粉红色表示
And so then the the blocks that aren't marked then we can free
然后那些没有标记的块然后我们就可以释放了
And return to the free list
并返回空闲列表
Okay so let's look at the assumptions for a simple implementation just to make sure this is clear
好的，让我们看一下这个假设的简单实现，能让大家更清楚
So the application calls new to get a pointer to a block with all the values cleared
应用程序调用 new 来获取指针指向清除所有值内存块
It calls read(b,i) to read location i of block b
它调用 read(b, i) 来读取块 b 的位置 i
And it uses write(b,i,v) to write a value v into location i of block b
并且它使用 write(b, i, v) 将值 v 写入块 b 的位置 i
Then each block will have a header word which will address as b[-1]
然后每个块将有一个头部字，其地址为 b[-1]
And then the garbage collector has
然后垃圾收集器
It has functions that it uses to identify whether a pointer
它具有用于识别指针的功能
Whether its input parameter is indeed a pointer
它的输入参数是否确实是一个指针
Okay so there's some way to distinguish a pointer from an on pointer
好的，有一些方法可以区分指针和指针
And it can get the length of some block
它可以得到一些块的长度
Not including the header and it can get a set of all of the routes
不包括头部，它可以获得一组所有路线
So given those assumptions
所以给出了这些假设
We a pseudocode for the mark step
我们是标记步骤的伪代码
So this initially is a pointer,a route pointer
所以这最初是一个指针，一个路由指针
Okay and then we check as a terminating condition
然后我们检查作为终止条件
We check to see if that input is indeed a pointer and if so we return
我们检查输入是否确实是指针，如果是，我们返回
Okay then we do a depth-first traversal of the of the graph
好的，然后我们对图表进行深度优先遍历
So if
因此，如果
And this...so we're doing a depth-first traversal of the graph and this is pointer is sort of our terminating condition for that
所以我们正在对图进行深度优先遍历，这是指针是我们的终止
That depth-first traversal
深度优先遍历的条件
Then we check the mark bit and if it's set then that's another terminating condition
然后我们检查标记位，如果它已设置，那么这是另一个终止条件
There's no reason to search once we find a marked node
一旦找到标记的节点，就没有理由进行搜索
We know that all of reachable nodes from that node is marked
我们知道从该结点出发的所有可以到达的结点都已经被标记
So we can terminate a return and just stop the search
所以我们可以终止，返回并停止搜索
If it's not set then we set the mark bit
如果没有设置，那么我们设置标记位
And then we look at each word in the block
然后我们看看块中的每个字
And we recursively call mark on each one of those words
我们递归地在每个字上调用标记
Now each one of those words may or may not be a pointer right
那么这些字中的每一个都可能是也可能不是指针
So if it's not a pointer then mark will just return instantly immediately
如果它不是指针，标记后马上返回
If it is a pointer then it will continue the recursive depth first search
如果它是一个指针，那么它将继续递归深度优先搜索
Okay so does that make make sense it's just the familiar def first graph traversal bit
理解了吗？这就是大家熟悉图的深度优先搜索算法
That we all know about
我们都知道
Okay and then the sweep, sweep takes a pointer to the beginning of the heap
好的，然后扫描，扫描采用指向堆的开头的指针
The first it takes a pointer to the first block in the heap
第一个是指向堆中第一个块的指针
And then some a pointer to the end of the heap
然后是一些指向堆末尾的指针
And then in a while loop then it scans the heap each block
然后在 while 循环中，它会扫描每个块的堆
If the mark bit is set it clears it
如果设置了标记位，则清除它
If it's allocated it frees it right
如果它被分配，释放它
And then it updates and then it gets the address of the the next block
然后它更新，然后它获取下一个块的地址
And then just continues until the end
然后继续直到结束
Okay so how do we do such a thing in C right
那么我们如何在 C 中做这样的事情吧
Because all of these assumptions I've made don't hold and C right you can't tell a pointer from a null pointer
因为我所做的所有这些假设不一定对，在 C 中你不能区分指向空指针的指针
Pointers can point anywhere
指针可以指向任何地方
So what you could do so the big issue is that
所以最大的问题是
If we get some value
如果我们得到一些值
It even if it is a pointer it could point right into the middle of the block
即使它是指针，它也可以指向块的中间
So given that
考虑到这些
So first of all we don't know if that value really is a pointer it could just be a big integer
首先，我们不知道该值是否真的是指针，它可能只是一个大整数
But it also could be a pointer that's pointing into some data structure
但它也可能是一个指向某些数据结构的指针
So if it is a pointer how do we find the beginning of the block
所以，如果它是一个指针，我们如何找到块的开头
So what we could do is just assume that
所以我们能做的就是假设
Every value is a pointer
每个值都是一个指针
And then we maintain a balance tree to keep track of all the allocated blocks
然后我们维护一个平衡树来跟踪所有已分配的块
And so whenever we encounter a particular value
所以每当我们遇到特定的价值时
We would search that binary tree to see if assuming it is a pointer
我们会搜索那个二叉树，看看它是否是一个指针
If it falls within the the beginning and end of some allocated block
如果它属于某个已分配块的开头和结尾
Okay if that condition is true then we assume that it's
如果那个条件是真的
Pointing that that's a pointer to an allocated block
我们假设它这个指针指向已分配块
And we assume that block is reachable
我们假设块可以访问
Now the reason it's conservative is because it really may not be a pointer it might be this integer
现在它保守的原因是因为它可能不是指针，它可能是这个整数
And we'll assume it's a pointer and assume that
我们假设它是一个指针
The block that it purportedly points to is allocated
并且假设它据称指向的块被分配
But it may in fact be not be a pointer and the block that
但它实际上可能不是指针和块
It points to is garbage
它指的是垃圾
Right so what with this scheme we would leave some non reachable blocks
所以使用这个方案我们会留下一些不可访问的块
We will indicate that some non reachable blocks are really reachable
我们将指出一些不可到访问的块确实可以访问
Okay so
然后
So once now that we've got this great tool to dynamically allocate memory
一旦我们有了这个动态分配内存的好工具
We can use it in our programs
我们可以在我们的程序中使用它
And shoot ourselves in the foot in all different kinds of ways
并且用各种各样的方式给自己带来一些麻烦
Okay so I'm going to try to help  help you out here by identifying
所以我打算用一些与内存相关的操作或者
Some of the perils and pitfalls that that we can run into with memory related operations or operations on memory
内存操作可能会遇到的一些危险和陷阱
And opera errors errors involving memory
涉及内存的的错误是
Are the worst the worst kinds of bugs to try to find out
最糟糕的一种漏洞
And the reason is that they're distant in both space and time
原因是他们在空间和时间上都很遥远
So let's say you write to the wrong memory location and corrupt some data structure
因此，假设你写入错误的内存位置并破坏某些数据结构
The right doesn't elicit any error
当下不会引起任何错误
You only find out about that erroneous right
当你尝试引用该数据结构或者数据结构中的特定部分的时候
When you try to reference that data structure or that particular part of the data structure
你才能够发现错误
Which may be in a part of the code that's way far away from the right that caused the problem
可能是离当前操作区域很远的代码的一部分导致了这个问题
Both in space you know in distance you know lines of code it could be a completely different function
可能是离当前的代码很远，也可能和当前的功能完全不同
And a completely different module
也可能是一个完全不同的模块
But also in time it may not you know you may do the right
当下，你可能运行正确
And then eons later other some read and it fails
然后很久以后其他人运行了一遍就失败了
Right so this is a fundamental thing that makes memory related bugs just so nasty
所以这个基本的东西使内存相关的错误如此讨厌
And another thing that makes them hard to deal with
另一件让他们难以应对的事情
Is people's misunderstanding and misuse of pointers right
是人们对指针的误解和误用
So usually an erroneous right is some is
所以通常一些错误就是
Some either a misunderstanding of pointers or an improperly initialized pointer
有些是对指针的误解或者是指针初始化不正确
So it all boils down to these pointers
这一切归结为指针
Okay and so I'm going to show you how to understand pointers
好的，我将向你展示如何理解指针
Okay for the first time in your lives
这是你生命中的第一次
I don't know about you but when I learned C
我不了解你，但是当我学习 C 时
I learned about pointers
我了解了指针
I just knew about what a few different types of pointers  were by and I did it by pattern matching
我只知道几个不同类型的指针是什么，我通过模式匹配来做到这一点
So I knew that int *p was a pointer to an int
所以我知道 int* p 是指向 int 的指针
I knew that int **p was an array
我知道 int** p 是一个数组
I knew that int *p
我知道 int* p
Open bracket closed bracket was also an array just a different way to  express that array
左括号和右括号也是另一种表达数组的方式
So I had a small handful of pointers types that I could deal with
我有一些我可以处理的指针类型
But I had no underlying understanding of what that meant or anything was just pure pattern matching
但我对这意味着什么并不了解，或者只是简单的模式识别
And I'll bet you that's the way you do it too
而且我敢打赌你也是这样做的
All right but that's all going to change today
但今天一切都会改变
All right so
好的
In order to really understand pointers
为了真正理解指针
You need to understand the precedence of various operators in C
你需要了解 C 中各种运算符的优先级
Because the pointer types are declared using these operators
因为使用这些运算符声明指针类型
And so my copy of k and r is it has a dog-eared at page 53
此内容在 k&r 第 53 页
This table comes from page 53 of K&R
此表来自 K&R 的第 53 页
And you should have a paper clip or have that folded over for reference
你应该有一个回形针或将它折叠起来作为参考
Now the thing to notice is that
现在需要注意的是
Function and array and then and these struct these various struct operators
函数和数组然后和这些结构这些各种 struct 运算符
Have the highest priority,highest precedence
拥有最高优先级
And that that's followed by unary operators so the star this is the dereference operator
接下来是一元运算符，所以 「*」 就是解除引用运算符
And then the address of operator
然后是地址运算符
The they fall right below
它们在
The highest precedence operators
最高优先级运算符的后面
And then the binary versions of operators you know that you use in arithmetic operations are below those
你知道在算术运算中使用的运算符的二进制版本的优先级低于这些运算符
Okay so just remember
所以请记住
That function and array is higher than *
该函数和数组的优先级高于 *
That too deep the dereference
这种解除引用太深了
Now the great thing about pointers although they always seem really complicated
现在关于指针的好处虽然它们看起来总是很复杂
Is that there's an algorithm for
这是一个算法吗？
It for there's an algorithm for
它有一个算法
Constructing an english sentence that explains exactly what that pointer
构造一个英语句子，准确地解释了那个指针
What that definition of the pointer means
指针的定义意味着什么
Okay and if you're interested it's in the K&R are in section 5.12
如果你对 K&R 感兴趣，请参阅第 5.12 节
But I'll explain it to you now
但我现在会向你解释
Now I don't know how much in this class you're going to remember
现在我不知道你会在这堂中学到多少
Okay but I guarantee you're going to remember this as the day you finally understood pointers okay
但我保证你会记住这一天，因为你终于理解指针了
So all
所以
Right so here's how it works
这是它的工作原理
You always start it the this is a definition of a pointer some kind
你总是这样开始，这是某种指针的定义
You always start with the variable name
你始终以变量名称开头
And then you use your precedence
然后你使用你的优先权
Then you look for operators on either side of that variable name
然后，你在该变量名称的任一侧查找运算符
And you choose the one that has the highest precedence
并且你选择具有最高优先级的那个
Okay so we start with the variable so we say p  is a
我们从变量开始，所以我们说 p 是一个
Then we look to the left and the right
然后我们向左看和向右看
There's nothing to the right but there's a there's a pointer symbol to the left
右边没什么，但是左边有一个指针符号
So we say p is a pointer
所以我们说 p 是一个指针
And there's nothing more and then we always end up with the type of thing that it points that
并没有更多，然后我们总是最终得到它所指出的那种东西
So p is a pointer to an int
所以 p 是指向 int 的指针
Right so p is
所以 p 是
P is a pointer to some integer in memory okay
P 是指向内存中某个整数的指针
So we all know that one that's pretty easy
这个非常简单
Okay what about the next one
下一个呢
You've probably seen something like this
你可能已经见过像这样的东西了
Some programs declare our v using this notation
有些程序使用这种表示法声明我们的 v
And so this you can have an optional size or not
所以你可以有一个可选尺寸
So we always star out we say p is a
所以我们说 p 是一个
Well now in this case there's operators to the left and the right
现在在这种情况下，左侧和右侧都有操作符
Remember the array operator has higher precedence than the dereferencing operator the pointer operators
请记住，数组运算符的优先级高于指针运算符
So we say so p is an array 13 array of size 13  of
所以我们说 p 是一个大小为 13 的数组
So there's nothing more so we go to the left of pointers
右边没有更多的东西，所以我们去指针的左边
So p is an array 13 of pointers to ints
所以 p 是一个由 13 个指向 int 的指针组成的数组
So p is an array of 13 pointers
所以 p 是一个由 13 个指针构成的数组
Each of which points to an int
每个都指向一个 int
Right in this case p is just the name of the array
在这种情况下，p 就是数组的名称
So by default p
默认情况下
P is equivalent is the address of the array
p 等价于数组的地址
When you reference an array name you're addressing your dressing the address of the first element
当你引用数组名称时，你正在寻找第一个元素的地址
Okay how about the next one
下一个怎么样
Here we're being if we put parentheses around things then we can be explicit
我们在这里，如果我们把括号放在事物周围，那么我们可以是明确的
Okay and this is a good practice
好的，这是一个很好的做法
So here we're saying p
所以我们在这里说 p
And we have to look at this one first because of the parentheses
由于括号，我们必须首先看一下这个
So p is an array[13] of pointers to ints
p 是一个指向由 13 个指向 int 的指针所构成的数组
So that's the same thing
所以这是一回事
And here we're just being more explicit
在这里，我们只是更明确
Now what about **p
现在怎么样 **p
So p is a pointer to a pointer to an int
p 是指向 int 的指针的指针
Okay so this is a different type of array
这是一种不同类型的数组
So p is a pointer to a pointer to an int
p 是指向 int 指针的指针
Okay and
好的
And typically so this is another way to do arrays
通常这是另一种产生数组的方法
So the same way the char* points to a string
所以 char* 指向字符串的方式相同
It points to a pointer but then you can index on that
它指向一个指针，然后你可以索引它
Each one of those then points corresponds to a pointer
其中每一个指向对应的指针
Whoops okay
哎呀
Here's another one now p because and because of the parentheses we have to go left
这是另一个，p 因为括号我们必须到左边
So p is a pointer to an array[13] of ints
p 是一个指向大小为 13 的 int 型数组的指针
Right now what about this one
现在怎么样呢
f is a function is...it a function or a pointer
f 是一个函数，它是一个函数或一个指针
f is a function right because of the precedence
由于优先权，f 是一个函数
So f is a function returning pointer to int
f 是一个返回 int 指针的函数
Ok so if we go
好的
If we go p=f
如果我们让 p = f
Then that returns that initialized p to point to some int
然后返回初始化的 p 指向某个 int
All right
好吧
And I'm going to do this one let's jump down in the interest of time
我打算这样做，让我们为了时间而跳下来
Totally ridiculous case just so you can see that this algorithm works
完全荒谬的情况，只是让你可以看到这个算法的工作原理
All right so x is an array of pointers
x 是一个指针数组
To functions returning pointers
返回指针的函数
To an array five int
指向 int 类型长度为 5 的数组
And if you ever use anything like that in your code
如果你在代码中使用过类似的东西
Shame on you
真丢脸
All right so there you go so that's
所以你打算怎么做
Now you know now you understand pointers
现在你了解了指针
Simple as can be and all you need is page 53 of K&R is a handy reference
尽可能简单，你可以参考 K&R 的第 53 页
All right so let's we'll take the last five minutes and I'll show you some
好吧，让我们在最后五分钟，我会告诉你们一些
Some of the ways you can trip yourself up
一些你可以绊倒自己的方法
When you're accessing memory
当你访问内存时
Okay so first is the classic scanf bug
首先是经典的 scanf 错误
You probably all done this where you forget to pass it the address of a variable instead you pass it the address
你可能都做到了这一点，你忘记传递变量的地址
So scanf doesn't know where to put the you know put the data
所以 scanf 不知道把数据放在哪里
Okay another common mistake is to read uninitialized memory
另一个常见错误是读取未初始化的内存
So suit you can't really assume that your heap data is initialized to 0
你不能真正假设你的堆数据初始化为 0
So here we're we're malloc an array of an int
这里我们使用 malloc 分配一个 int 的数组
And then we're going through and we're doing
我们正在做
We're updating this vector
我们正在更新此向量
This y vector we're reading y[i]
这个 y 矢量我们正在读 y[i]
We're taking y[i] = y[i] + a[i][j]*x[j]
我们使 y [i] = y [i] + a [i] [j] * x [j]
Okay so we're using we're assuming that y that malloc returns memory that's all zeros
所以我们正在使用我们假设那个 malloc 返回全部为零的内存
So that'll get you
这会让你
It's also easy to allocate the wrong sized object
分配错误大小的对象也很容易
So here we want to create
我们想在这里创建
An array of n pointers of n pointers to ints
一组 n 个指针，指向 int 的 n 个指针
Okay and then for each one we want to allocate m ints
然后我们想要分配 m 个整数
All right so this work we're creating a two-dimensional array
这项工作我们正在创建一个二维数组
And can you see the mistake which
你能看出错误吗？
Which line is buggy this one
哪一行有问题
This one or this one
这一个或这一个
The first one right because we really want size int star
第一行！因为我们想要是 int *
Right so we're erroneous incorrectly assuming that int are the same sizes as pointers
我们错误地认为 int 与指针的大小相同
This is a classic
这是非常经典的错误
On this this assumption is true for 32-bit code
对此，这种假设适用于 32 位代码
Ints and pointers are the same size but it's not true for 64-bit
Ints 和指针的大小相同，但对于 64 位则不然
And so this is why when you...when people port 32-bit code to 64-bit machine a lot of times it breaks
所以这就是为什么当人们将 32 位代码移植到 64 位机器时很多时候它会中断
Because they have this assumption
因为他们有这个假设
Okay another way you it's easy to overwrite memory
另一种方式是你很容易覆盖内存
So here we're creating correctly creating this array
所以我们正在创建这个数组
But then when we create each of the sub arrays
但是当我们创建每个子数组时
Instead of i less than or equal to n we're actually
我实际上并没有小于或等于 N
We only created n of these things but we're traversing n+1
我们只创建了这些东西，但我们正在遍历 N + 1
Because of this less than or equal
因为这个小于或等于
So this is a classic off by one bug
所以这是一个经典的错误
Ok another problem you saw it with the code injection attacks from your attack lab
好的另一个问题是你从 attack lab 看到的代码注入攻击
Not checking the the size of a buffer
不检查缓冲区的大小
So get ass is a classic example of this
所以缓冲区溢出就是一个典型的例子
So that will get you into trouble
这样会让你陷入困境
Another another classic mistake is misunderstanding pointer arithmetic
另一个经典错误是误解指针算术
All right so if you increment a pointer
如果你增加一个指针
Then it's incremented by the size of the object that pointer points to
然后它增加指针所指向的对象的大小
Right so if you increment an int *  by one
如果你将 int* 递增 1
It actually increments it by 4
它实际上将它增加 4
Because that's the size of an int
因为那是 int 的大小
He's got that's a really important distinction
他有这个非常重要的区别
And so people will often
所以人们会经常这样
So here it's assuming that incrementing so p is a pointer
所以这里假设递增，因为 p 是一个指针
And the programmer here assumed that he wants to increment the pointer to sort of traverse it
并且程序员在这里假设他想要将指针递增以达到遍历数组的目的
An array so he doesn't understand pointer arithmetic
他不懂指针算术
And so to get to the next int increments  p by size int
所以要通过 size(int) 来获得下一个 int 增量 p
Okay this will really increment it by 16 not by 4
这会增加 16 而不是 4
Okay overriding memory that's a really nasty one
好内存覆盖是一个非常讨厌的
And a lot of times this can happen if you don't understand the precedence of the operators
很多时候，如果你不了解运算符的优先级，就会发生这种情况
That you're working with
你正在使用它们
So this is a heap not too kind of heap we've been talking about but oh the heap data structure
所以这是一堆不是我们一直在讨论的那种堆，而是堆数据结构
And this is a function to delete from a heap
这是一个从堆中删除的功能
And this actually is from my own code I have to admit
我必须得承认这其实是来自我自己的代码
And so I want to delete in it an element
我想在其中删除一个元素
I want to delete the first element of the heap
我想删除堆的第一个元素
Right and then I want to reify it
后我想要实现它
Okay so I and then I want to return, I want to return that
然后我想返回这个
So I get the first element the heap
我得到堆的第一个元素
I decreased the size of the heap
我减小了堆的大小
I take the last element and make that the first element
我拿出最后一个元素并将其作为第一个元素
And and now I want to decrease the size of the heap
现在我想减小堆的大小
Because this delete operation will delete the heap size by one
因为此删除操作会将堆大小删除一个
So notice here we passed size n as a pointer
所以请注意，我们将 「size」作为指针传递
And when this when this function terminate
而当这个功能终止时
When this function return size should be updated size as a pointer the value that it points to you should be decremented
当这个函数返回 size 所指向的值会被更新，它将会减少
Okay that's our intent
这是我们的意图
And we do it right here with the *size--
我们就在这里用 *size--
So what we want to do is we want to dereference size
所以我们想做的是我们想要取消引用大小
And then decrement that value
然后递减该值
But because the unary minus minus has higher of precedence than then the dereference
但是因为「一元减」的优先级高于取消引用的优先级
What we're really doing is we're decrementing the pointer
我们真正在做的是我们减少指针
And then dereferencing the value that's
然后解除引用的值
One word less than a size variable
一个小于 size 一字的变量
All right so these are nasty
这些都很讨厌
And it would have been much cleaner
它本来会更简洁
If I had just put parentheses around like I intended just parentheses star sized parentheses
如果我只是把括号括起来，就像我打算用圆括号星号括起来一样
Alright another way you can mess up is referencing forgetting the local variables disappear
另一种方法你可以搞砸是引用忘记局部变量消失
So if you have a function that returns an address of a local variable no good
所以如果你有一个函数返回一个局部变量的地址，这一点都不好
Okay no good at all
一点也不好
It might be okay for a while until somebody another function reuses that space
一段时间可能没关系，直到某人有另一个功能重用该空间
That could be a return address it could be another functions local variable
这可能是一个返回地址，它可能是另一个函数局部变量
Another terrible mistake this is a really bad one is freeing a block multiple time
另一个可怕的错误是一个非常糟糕的错误是多次释放一个块
Now you know from your understanding now of malloc
现在你从现在对 malloc 的了解中得知
That free actually writes to the heap right it's coalescing it's changing pointers
这个 free 实际上写入了堆，它正在合并它正在改变的指针
It's changing size block sizes
它正在改变块大小
So if you free a block that's already been freed terrible things will happen
如果你释放一块已经被释放的块，那么可怕的事情就会发生
Another thing you can do wrong is to reference a block you forget that you freed a block and then you reference
你可能做错的另一件事是引用一个块，你忘了你释放了一个块然后你引用
It so here we free of this block x
在这里我们释放了这个块 x
And then we're referencing it here
然后我们在这里引用它
Another big problem is
另一个大问题是
Memory leaks so failing to free block so allocating some block
内存泄漏，无法释放块，因此分配了一些块
Function and then returning
然后函数返回
That block will stay there forever right because it's garbage
那块将永远留在那里因为它是垃圾
Okay so there's a number of ways to deal with memory bugs
有很多方法可以处理内存错误
GDB is sometimes good at least it'll tell you where a segfault occurs
GDB 有时候很好，它至少可以告诉你 segfault 发生在哪里
Then you got to track down what the right that
然后你必须找到正确的
Sort of caused that segfault
排序导致了段错误的位置
The best thing you can do
你能做的最好的事情
But GDB falls down whenever you're doing manipulation of complex data structures
但是，只要你正在操纵复杂的数据结构，GDB 就会崩溃
It's just simple sort of looking one instruction at a time
它只是简单地一次查看一条指令
What you really need to do is identify any complex data structure like a heap for example
你真正需要做的是识别任何复杂的数据结构，例如堆
Is identify invariance for that structure that data structure should always maintain
确定数据结构应始终保持的结构的不变性
And then you write a function
然后你写一个函数
That iterates over that structure that data structure and checks that all those they're invariants are true
迭代数据结构时，检查所有那些不变量的结构是否为真
So for example in it
例如
And in allocator one of the invariance is that there should be no
在分配器中，其中一个不变性是
That there should never be two contiguous free blocks
永远不应该有两个连续的空闲块
Right so your consistency checker should go through the heap and make sure there's no contiguous free blocks
所以你的一致性检查器应该通过堆并确保没有连续的空闲块
Or another invariant is that every free block should be in a free list somewhere
或者另一个不变量是每个空闲块应该在某个地方的空闲列表中
Right so you would up your consistency checker would scan the heap count the number of free blocks
你想你的一致性检查器将扫描堆计数空闲块的数量
And then scan the free list and make sure
然后扫描空闲列表并确保
That the number of blocks in the free list is the same as the number of free blocks
空闲列表中的块数与空闲块的数量相同
Okay so this idea of a consistency checker is something you'll use in your malloc lab
我们会在 malloc  lab 中使用一致性检查器
But it's something it's also something you should use whenever you're updating any kind of complex data structure
但是，无论何时更新任何类型的复杂数据结构，都应该使用它
And you know about valgrind but the great thing about these heap checkers
你知道 valgrind，但关于这些堆检查器
Ok I'm passionate about heap checkers
我对堆检查器很有热情
Or consistency checkers
或一致性检查员
The really powerful thing about them is you write them to run silently
关于它们的真正强大之处在于你将它们写成静默运行
They don't print anything unless they find that a violation of the invariance
除非他们发现违反不变性，否则他们不会打印任何内容
If you write your consistency checker like this then you can use it like a probe
如果你像这样编写一致性检查器，那么你可以像探测器一样使用它
So your program crashes
你的程序崩溃了
So you do it you use this heap checker to do a binary search to isolate the cause
你这样做，你使用这个堆检查器进行二进制搜索，以找出原因
So you know you put your heap checker here
所以你知道你把堆检查器放在这里
Everything is ok
一切都好
And then later the program crash
然后程序崩溃了
So now you stick the heap checker here
所以现在你把堆检查器粘在这里
And now it crash the heap checker detects an in violation
现在崩溃堆检查器检测到违规
So you know that the problem is somewhere here
所以你知道这个问题就在这里
And you can just keep narrowing it down so it's just like a probe
你可以继续缩小范围，这就像探测器一样
Surgical probe that you can use to to track down bugs
你可以用来追踪错误的手术探针
And so that's if you do this like it's
如果你像这样做的话
I don't know how anybody debugs malloc without this kind of tool
我不知道有没有人在没有这种工具的情况下调试 malloc
Okay so that's it for today
好的，这就是今天的内容
Have a good weekend we'll see you on Tuesday
祝周末愉快，周二我们会见到你